Salvatore Fiengo

Collection Team Leader

Address Shandon Mill, Dublin, D07

Phone 0834320505

E-mail sal.fiengo@gmail.com

WWW https://github.com/SalvatoreFiengo

Collection Team Leader and graduated web developer with diploma in Full Stack Software Development with Python certified (MS) offering enthusiasm and understanding of various programming languages. In current role, further programming experience gathered while developing a leave tracker desktop app as extra task.

Skills

HTML 5 expertise	
JavaScript expertise	
Credit and collections specialist	
Web Standards	
Git	
Communication Skills	
Python expertise	
Team Leadership Skills	
React expertise	
CSS3 expertise	
JQuery expertise	
Django Web Framework expertise	
Web Development Projects	
Web User Interfaces	

Work History

2020-06 - Current

Collections Team Leader

Accenture, Dublin, Dublin Co.

- Supervised staff of collectors, monitoring phone calls and Emails.
- Kept accurate and detailed records of personnel progress and productivity.
- Evaluated employee skills and knowledge regularly, providing hands-on training and mentoring to individuals with lagging skills.
- Coordinated schedules and reviewed work performance for staff.

- Oversaw talented team of 15 Collection agents by actively communicating project information, remedying issues and delivering positive feedback.
- Created support documentation that empowered and enabled user community to extend skills and find solutions to questions without help from seniors and team leaders.

2016-07 - 2020-07 Senior Credit Collections Analyst

Accenture, Dublin, Dublin

- Best collector year 2018
- Performed credit reviews on corporations to assess financial conditions.
- Made decisions and recommendations about extending lines of credit.
- Worked in tandem with sales team and customers to negotiate payments and verify account reconciliations.
- Improved understanding of financial statements, which helped in assessing risk.
- Reviewed customer files on regular basis to make sure receivables were in sound condition.
- Minimized accounts receivable collections and reconciled customer billings and statements.
- Complied with internal controls and government regulations.
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving billing issues.

2015-10-2016-09 Technical Customer Support

Accenture, Dublin, Dublin

- Devised solutions to operations issues related to vary systems including Office 365 and OS Windows, working closely via phone, email and web teleconference.
- Assessed system hardware and software and suggested modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall speed.
- Documented all transactions and support interactions in system for future reference and addition to knowledge base.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- QIP Quality Initiative Program: Direct ticket escalation without supervision
- Quality rate: over95%
- New hires coaching and ticket quality supervision.

2015-06 - 2015-08 Field Sales Representative

Ace 8 Media - Dublin Ireland, Dublin, Co. Dublin

- Identified prospect needs and developed appropriate responses along with information on suitable products and services.
- Demonstrated products and specific features at customer locations (B2B).

2014-02 - 2014-08 Technical Support Apprentice

Agic Technologies, Rome, Italy

 Performed Troubleshooting of all information system/application issues for over 120 users.

- Desktop, Laptop, Mobile devices support, remotely and on site
- Customers service for external business customers and private persons, remotely and on site.

2010-02-2013-07 Field Sales Agent

Sky Italia SRL, Rome, Italy

- Direct sales to private individuals and businesses
- Coaching experience with external personnel
- Negotiation, soft sale, and hard sale experience.

Education

2021-02 MTA – Python certification

2018-01 - 2019-02 Diploma: Full Stack Diploma in Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin

- Grade: First Class Honors
- HTML,
- Css3,
- Bootstrap,
- · Sass,
- JavaScript,
- jQuery,
- APIs,
- Basics of DC and D3.
- Python Fundamentals,
- Practical Python,
- Data Centric Development,
- Django (Python framework)

Accomplishments

- One of the winners of CICM's "Collections team of the year", represented Accenture in related event, reported on newspapers such "The Sunday Business Post" (4/11/2018 – titled "Where it is due")
- Creation and maintenance of a Knowledge bank for Collections and IT dept.
 using shared MS One Note that greatly improved productivity in other teams as
 well.
- Developed an intranet desktop "Leave tracker app" using Django and Electron.